A Guide to the Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA802 FA802
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
  - SUBJECT FILES (Box 24)
    - History of Medicine (Box 24)
      - [Notes, outlines, tables, including notes on reading, quotations, references, and reflections by Cohn] (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
      - Notes on History of Heart Diseases [Figure, chronology, notes, outline] (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Levy, R.L. Quinidine notes on Experiments. R.L. Levy and A.E. Cohn, circa 1921 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Macleod, A.G. and Cohn, A.E.A new piezo-electric manometer which records intracardiac pressures and for the simultaneous recording of intracardiac electrograms (Box 24, Folder 14)
      [Typescripts, correspondence].
    - Neumann, C., Cohn, A.E. and Burch, G.E.A quantitative method for measurement of the rate of water loss from small areas etc., [Page proof, galleys, data, typescript, figures] (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Neumann, C: Graef, I. Proskauer, G.G. and Neumann, C. The influence of the body temperature and the application of heat on the blood pressure of rats. Abstract submitted to Soc. Exper. Biol. Med. for, 1943 March; [Typescript and letter] (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Neumann, C.A. Study of the Effect of Spontaneous Variations in Blood Pressure upon Spontaneous Variations in the volume of the Finger Tip, [Galley, figure, typescript] [d] (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Neumann, C., Grunfest, H., Berry, C.M. Rule and cohen, A.E. Return of function of sweat glands after cutting or crushing sympathetic nerves. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. & Med., 54, 27, 1943; [Reprint, typescript] (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Notes (Box 24)
      - Notes on Rabies in R.I. Epidemic, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Bacteriology (Notes) (Box 24, Folder 20)
        [Includes undated note by O.T. Avery, Cohn notes, historical tables on discovery of organisms of diseases].
      - Notes for meetings. 1) NY Acad. Med. 2) ditto. Section meeting, 1916 December 7; [Typescripts] (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Notes on the Administration of Digitalis in Lobar Pneumonia in the R.I.H., 1925 November 19 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Notes: Various important! [Notes re galvanometer (?), pneumonia, data, drawings and diagrams, letter to Rufus Cole, M.D. re Miss Craig's salary], 1921 January 27 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Notes on digitalis (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Notes on Patients, circa 1913? (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Pardee, H.E.B., 1920 February 20 (Box 24, Folder 26)
      [Pardee/Cohn, and typescripts].
    - Dr. H.E.B. Pardee. Heart of Wm. Goodheart (Box 24, Folder 27)
      [N.B. Folders of PHOTOGRAPHS moved to biographical files].
    - Pneumonia - Irregularities [Notes, references] (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Reports: - 1)XVII International Congress 2) Amer. Assoc. Experimental Pharmac. & Therapeutics, [Holographs, typescripts, galleys, of scientific papers] (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Reviewed for Central bl. f. Herz. etc. [Cohn summaries of articles by other authors], circa 1912-1913 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - untitled (Box 24)
      - [Correspondence, memoranda, re cardio-vascular examination of men returned from active military service; medical record forms (multiple copies of blank forms discarded)], 1919 (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - [Notes, photos, medical histories] (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - [Filled-out cardiovascular record forms], 1919 (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - [Notes, data, tables] (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - [Filled-out cardiovascular record forms and correspondence] (Box 24)
        - #1-69 (Box 24, Folder 35)
        - #70-129 (Box 24, Folder 36)
        - #130-219 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - [X-rays-photographs] (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - [Correspondence and cardiovascular records, re fitness of recruits for service, in following classifications: Miscellaneous, Navy, Marine Corps, Unidentified service, British Royal Flying Corps and Recruiting Mission], circa 1917-1918 (Box 24, Folder 39-42)
    - Captain Stevens (Box 24, Folder 43)
      [Corrected typescript, "An Unusual Case of Heart Acceleration and Irregularity", electrocardiograms].
    - Heart from Dr. W.S. Thayer. [Post mortem record], 1917 March 29 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Cohn miscellaneous notes, 1940-1942 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Including lists of names, notes for speech at International House, 19 April 1942.
    - re Science Legislation (Box 25)
      - [Note cards of names and addresses, some out of original order] (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Printed materials (Box 25, Folder 3)
        Including 1945 "Hearings on Science Legislation (S. 1297 and Related Bills)." Parts 1-4.
      - Open Letter to The President [Printed letter by Cohn, 18 Dec 1945 (Multiple copies discarded), correspondence, mss] (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Bills [U.S. Senate ca 1945-46], 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Need for Kilgore Bill NY Times July 2, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Bush Plan is Disapproved NY Times Aug. 30, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Debate Held Necessary NY Times - Sept 30, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Research Body Urged (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - NY Times - Dec. 9, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Letter to Editor - Science April 5, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Newspaper cuttings re Science Legislation (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - [Papers from Desk File: Folders on subjects, Correspondence A-Z] (Box 25)
        - [Correspondence, notes, ca 1947-49], 1947-1949 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Legislating Science. NY Times, Dec 29, 1946; Science Legislation Opposed - Feb. 24, 1947. [Cohn letter and subsequent reply] counter-reply with W. Parker Anslow, Jr.], 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Science Foundation Opposed. NY Times. Aug. 5, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Anslow, W. Parker (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Bob, Jacob (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Bush, Vannevar [clipping] (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Carson, John (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Conant, President (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Cooper, Edward (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Day, Edmund E. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Delman, David (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Dewey, Bradley (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Ellsworth, Harris (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Fosdick, Mr. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Fulbright, J.W. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Gaus, John M. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Gerard, R.W. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Gray, H.M. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Griggs, Robert F. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Harcourt. Brace & Co. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Hecht, Selig (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Jewett, F.B. (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Kamm, George N. (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Kilgore, H.M. (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - King, Robert W. (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Klagsbrunn, Hans A. (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Kolb, Nellie M. (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Kramer, Charles (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Lasker, Albert D. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Lea, Clarence F. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Lowenthal, Max C. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Magnuson, Warren G. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Mead, James M. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Merz, Charles (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Meyer, Eugene (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Moe, Mr. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Niles, Dave (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Olson, Paul (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - O'Neill, John J. (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - The President (Box 25, Folder 15)
        - Paley, Mrs. William S. (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Palmer, Walter W. (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Parsons, Geoffrey (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Richards, A.N. (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Shapley, Harlow (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - Smith, Homer W. (Box 25, Folder 18)
        - Stem, Carl S. (Box 25, Folder 19)
        - Saltonstall, Leverett (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Schimmel, Herbert (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Seymour, Charles Shuster, George N. (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Smith, H. Alexander (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Smith, Frank Fremont-Taft, Robert A. [and other senators] (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Teeter, John H. [includes carbon copy of "Memo re Manhattan District. Check records of Alsos Mission 1-15-46 JHT, " sent to Cohn by mistake] (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Thomas, Elbert D. (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Valentine, Willard L. [Editor, Science] (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Wagner, Robert F. (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Weiss, Louis S. (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Whitaker, Douglas (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Willey, Grafton H., III (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Wolfle, Dael (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Boston, Cohn address, "Federal Legislation in Support of Science", published in Political Science Quarterly June 1947, 1946 December 28 (Box 25, Folder 22-23)
        Includes ms drafts, reprint, Atlantic Monthly Nov 1946.
      - Correspondence Mills, Krout, Gregg etc. Kaempffert [Miscellaneous correspondence, ca 1945-47. No letters to/ from W. Kaempffert found in this file], 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Dr. Cohn's work sheets - notes, etc. (Box 25, Folder 25)
        [Folder front cover has note, "This bill is a way of destroying not of creating scientists." Includes clippings, notes, Science issues].
      - Bush-Shapley - Times. [No correspondence from Bush or Shapley seems to be in this file. Primarily correspondence, clippings, congressional documents, re science legislation and Cohn letters to New York Times] (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Nat. Science Foundation. Summer 1947 [Clippings, Cohn reprint, brochure from The Foundation for Economic Education], 1947 July (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Science Bills - Letters returned by F.F. [Material loaned to Felix Frankfurter] (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Mimeographed copies sent to Senators and Representatives on Committee re Legislation () [Stationery box with copies of Cohn letter, 5 Mar 1947, and Pol. Sci. Quat. article for distribution. Multiple copies discarded], 1947 January (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - Printed materials (Box 25, Folder 30)
        Including Science the Endless Frontier by Vannevar Bush, congressional documents, etc.
      - [Memorandum, "Analysis of Legislation now Pending in Congress with regard to a Postwar Program for Scientific Research", with cover note from Jonas S. Fridenwald, nd. Two versions of memo, included] (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - [Congressional record], 1947 July 16 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - [Science clipping, 14 Jul 1944; various Science issues, Aug 1945-25 Jan 1946], 1944 July 14 1945 August-1946 January 25 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - COHN PERSONAL (Box 26)
    [This box consists of miscellaneous materials whose provenance is unknown. It was partly inventoried about a year ago, but has been reorganized and additions made. C. Kopp].
    - Medical records of A.E. Cohn, 1899, 1925, 1931. See also oversize (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Miscellany. Clipping; program; E. Craig memo (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - MANUSCRIPTS OF SCIENTIFIC ARTICLES (Box 26)
    - On the crescendo murmur in mitral stenosis, circa 1910 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - A case of transient complete auriculo-ventricular dissociation, showing constantly varying ventricular complexes, circa 1913 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - The effort syndrome, circa 1918 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Pathological examination of the heart in a case of complete dissociation n.d. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - NOTES, DATA, MANUSCRIPT DRAFTS, ETC, 1910 (Box 26)
    Auer, Dr. John EKG? 8 British Medical Association Exhibit labels, 1910.
    - Auer, Dr. John EKG? (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - British Medical Association Exhibit labels, 1910 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Calibration of? — [Unidentified apparatus] (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Cardiac outpatients. [Lists of names] (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Catalogue [Numbering system for medical subjects, perhaps used for reprint file? ] (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Griffith Heart (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - His Bundle Experiments, circa 1909; 2 folders (Box 26, Folder 13-14)
    - Kittlinien, circa 1909 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      Includes program of Deutsche Pathologische Gesellschaft Vienna 1909 meeting, with lecture by Cohn "24. Zur Frage der Kittlinien der Herzmuskulatur".
    - Meltzer, Dr. Oxygen experiments. Data, 1917; 2 folders (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
      Includes mounted photo of apparatus connected to subject's arm, with caption signed by Harry D. Clough, M.D.
    - [Patients] Records of leads, time, field, 1918 January 2-1919 May 15; 3 folders (Box 26, Folder 18-20)
    - Payne, Mrs. with Lewis and Holmes, circa 1911 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Van Slyke, Dr. Donald. EKG's? (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - PRINTED MATERIALS (Box 26)
    - Cohn, Edwin J. Reprints (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Haifa, Annual Report of the Department of Health, Malaria Research Unit, 1923 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Jerusalem. Annual Report of the Principal Medical Officer, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - League of Nations published materials on China, circa 1931-1934 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Mt. Sinai Hospital."Die Grosse Klystir II" 28 June 1907. [Satire] (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Record of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York. Vol. 1, No. 1 Feb 1946, with article by Oscar M. Ruebhausen, "Science: A Problem in Legislation" (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Royal Commission on Oxford and Cambridge Universities. Report, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Science issues, some with AEC annotations, 1946 January-1947 April; 2 folders (Box 26, Folder 30-31)
  - "E" files and Miscellaneous papers, 1981-1982
    Arrangement note
    The papers were found in considerable disorder, and the order below was given to aid retrieval of particular files/items. The group appears to be essentially an "E" correspondence file, but is not simply an omission from the correspondence already processed: there are an unusual number of family letters, as well as a number of items pre-1920, which distinguish this from the other correspondence.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    The following files, continued in Paige box 28, are a special group of papers that were received in April 1982 from Dr. John Crow (New York Hospital); Dr. and Mrs. Crow bought the former Cohn residence in New Milford, Ct., in the fall of 1981. The papers were discovered in the attic of the guest house; for further background see the Archivist's administrative file on the Cohn Papers.
    - "E" files
      - Ea (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Ed (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Educational Alliance, circa 1899-1912 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Eh-Ei (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Ehrich, Adelaide Price (Addie), circa 1902-1943; 2 folders (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
      - Ehrich, Robert (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Ehrich, Wilhelm (William) and Maïse, circa 1927-1948 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Einstein, Albert. Clippings, circa 1925-1945 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Einstein, Frank and Myra, circa 1896-1910 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Einstein, Milly J., circa 1900-1903 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Einstein, S.A., circa 1900-1907 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - El (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Eliot, Charles W. Clippings (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Elkus, Gleason, and Proskauer (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Elliott, Eva (Teddy), circa 1907-1908 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Ellis, Arthur M.W. and Winifred, circa 1915-1947 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Em (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - En (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Entenmann, Mrs. Paul (Edith)
      - Eq (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Erdmann, Mrs. William (Julie) and family ca 1911, 1916-48, und. [in folders by year], 1911 1916-1948
      - Er (Box 27, Folder 57)
      - Erlanger, Joseph, 1912 1944 (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - Ernst, Bernard M.L., circa 1899-1910 (Box 27, Folder 59)
      - Erskine, John ca 1900-10, 1941, clippings, circa 1900-1910 1941 (Box 27, Folder 60)
      - Es (Box 27, Folder 61)
      - Eu-Ev-Ew (Box 27, Folder 63)
      - E Unidentified (Box 27, Folder 64)
      - Europe, Memorabilia from trips to 1907-1909, 1912, 1913, 1920, 1922 (2 folders), 1925-26 (2 folders), 1927, 1928, 1907-1909 1912-1913 1920 1922 1925-1928 (Box 27, Folder 65-75)
        Arranged in folder by year.
      - Europe, Memorabilia, 1931; 3 folders (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
      - Europe Memorabilia, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 28)
      - A (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - B (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Clippings (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Columbia College (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Duggan, Mrs. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - F (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - H (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - J (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - L (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Unidentified correspondence (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous family letters and papers (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Bills, orders [primarily for books and scientific apparatus] 20-21, 1908-1909; 3 folders (Box 28, Folder 17-19)
      - Envelopes, circa 1910-1948; 2 folders (Box 28, Folder 20-21)
  - New York Times Letters to the Editor (Box 28)
    Includes correspondence, clippings of AEC letters and related articles, drafts.
    - Merz, Charles, 1945-1947 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Letter, published 6 May 1940".The Maintenance of Peace. Argument is Advanced that It is Not Always Supreme Desideratum" (Box 28, Folder 23-26)
    - Letter, 28 May 1940 (not published). Sequel to above (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Letter, published 25 Aug 1940".Wilkie's Speech. Republican Nominee Said to Have Ignored Issues" (Box 28, Folder 28-30)
    - Letter, published 6 Oct 1940 (?). [No clipping, No correspondence with NY Times in file] (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Letter, 4 Dec 1942 (not sent). re letter by Professor E.K. Rand published 2 Dec 1942 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Letter, 9 Sep 1943 (not published). To Book Reviews Editor, re review of William Percy's poems by Mr. Thorp (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Letter, published 2 July 1944".Need for Kilgore Bill. Background Issues That Bill Aims to Assist are Clarified" (Box 28, Folder 34-36)
    - Letter, published 17 Jan 1945".Grants-in-Aid Inadequate. Dependence on Foundations for Medical Research Regarded as Faulty" (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Letter, 24 May 1945 (not published). re German surrender and premature release by Mr. Kennedy (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Letter, published 30 August 1945".Bush Plan is Disapproved. Scientific Research Recommendations Held to Require Study" (Box 28, Folder 39-42)
    - Letter, published 30 Sep 1945".Debate Held Necessary. Full Adoption of Bush Report Far-Reaching Question" (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Letter, published 9 Dec 1945".Research Body Urged. Magnuson Bill Held to Lack An Important Detail" (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Article, 2 Jan 1946".Cohn Assails Bills on Science Research" (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, clippings re P.R. [Proportional Representation], 1941 1947 (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Minerva's Progress, by AEC (Harcourt, Brace, and Co., 1946)
    [Most of these papers were in unlabeled folders, with no clear indication of the internal order. The manuscript drafts have been put in chronological order insofar as possible; undated manuscripts are in alphabetical order by the first line of text. A few miscellaneous notes and loose pages are filed at the end of the series, as are a group of papers found in a stationery box labeled "Discarded sheets"].
    - Correspondence, Harcourt, Brace, and Co. (Box 28)
      - Giroux, Robert, 1945-1946 (Box 28, Folder 46-47)
      - Morley, Frank V., 1944-1946 (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - Schneider, Doris, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - Laski, Harold J., Comment on book, 1945 December 5 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Manuscripts, 1944 December 4-1945 December 4 (Box 28, Folder 51-76)
    - Manuscripts, 1945 December 18 1950 May 17 (?) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 29, Folder 3-12)
    - Manuscripts, "Discarded sheets" (Box 29, Folder 13-15)
    - untitled, Galley, page proof (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Scientific Reports, 1921 1925 1926 1930 1931 1935 1985
      This file was found in good order, though reports for some years/periods are missing. The series comprises primarily drafts by Cohn of reports to The Rockefeller Institute Board of Scientific Directors (April report) and to the Board of Trustees (October report) (other months, from the earliest years, are to the Bd. Sci. Dirs.). Also extant are a number of shorter reports prepared by Cohn's associates, which were incorporated by Cohn into the final version; some show Cohn's editorial revisions. In addition to these manuscript drafts, three soft-paper notebooks were found, containing the final reports for the years, respectively, April 1921-October 1925, April 1926-April 1930, and April 1931-March 1935. These reports have been removed from the notebooks and are filed at the beginning, of the period covered. Carolyn Kopp, 1 August 1985.
      - Reports, 1913 April-1929 October (Box 29, Folder 17-43)
      - Reports, 1930 March-1945 March (Box 30, Folder 1-19)
      - Report "The 'clinic' of the coronary arteries...", undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - NRR HB ms pp 1-352 (Box 30, Folder 21-27)
      - NRR Blve I-IV (Box 30, Folder 25-28)
      - NRR ms Drafts (Box 30, Folder 29-30)
    - Minerva's Progress. Galley proof. Reprints, unsorted, by Cohn and associates (Box 31)
  - Reprints by Cohn and associates (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Assorted papers, provenance unknown (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 32)
    - Home for Aged and Infirm Hebrews, 1937; 2 folders, Printed materials (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
  - Manuscripts (Box 32)
    - Burden of Diseases, 6 folders, Typescript with printer's marks (Box 32, Folder 5-10)
    - Flexner, Simon (Box 32, Folder 11-13)
      (see Minerva's Progress). Manuscript drafts by Cohn, notes, printed materials.
    - No Retreat from Reason. Miscellaneous notes etc., [ck: 8 Aug 1985] (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Notes and data (Box 32)
    - Experimental studies of quinidine. Cohn and Levy, 1921 November-1922 March; 2 folders (Box 32, Folder 15-16)
    - Notebook of photographic prints; possibly record of slides?, circa 1920s; 5 folders (Box 32, Folder 17-21)
    - Notes from binder, circa 1923-1930; 2 folders (Box 32, Folder 22-23)
    - Tissue culture notes, 7 folders (Box 32, Folder 24-30)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Giroux, Robert (Harcourt, Brace and Co), 1946-1948 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Correspondence.
    - Institute for Religious and Social Studies, The Jewish Theological Seminary of America. re "Spiritual Autobiography" lecture series, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Cohn lecture scheduled in 1946-47 catalogue for 18 Feb 1947. (See also mss. and Minerva's Progress). Also includes draft of lecture by M.L. Wilson, delivered 4 Feb 1947.
  - Manuscripts (Box 33)
    - A case of nodal bradycardia, circa 1908; 5 folders (Box 33, Folder 3-5)
      [Includes letters, Nov 1908-Aug 1909, by/about patient Mr. W. Newbigging].
    - Post-mortem examination of a case of auricular fibrillation and heart block, circa 1911 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - On the differences in the effects of stimulation of the two vagus nerves on rate and conduction of the dog's heart, circa 1912; 3 folders (Box 33, Folder 7-9)
    - Burden of Diseases. 3rd and 4th revisions, circa 1948-1949; 7 folders, graphs (Box 33, Folder 10-16)
    - Spiritual Biography, 4 folders (Box 33, Folder 17-20)
  - Notes and notebooks (Box 33)
    - Account book, Cohn lab, 1915 August-1917 March; 2 folders (Box 33, Folder 21-22)
    - Notebook, 1922 November-1923 March (Box 33, Folder 23)
      [Includes observations on chicken embryos].
    - Van Leersum (?) Dog Record, circa 1920-1921 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Printed materials (Box 33)